本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigamiorg)制作仅供交流学习禁止用于任何商业用途
Karasuno                   Waku South
日听：小伍King翻译：森罗小江校对：Syura时间轴：海底压制：Coolkid
Sorry.
ごめんちょと便所行てくる
I'm gonna go to the bathroom,
so go on ahead without me.
から先行てて
ずいぶん気合入れて便所行くんだな
He's really pumped about going to the bathroom.
He must need to shit.
クソなんだろ
Say "poop"! You're so vulgar, Kageyama!
うんこて言えよ影山くんお下品
Shit.
トイレに行たんじゃないと思うけど
I don't think he's actually going to the bathroom.
うんこ
Poop.
Shit
うんこ
Poop.
Shit.
うんこ
Poop!
Mr. Ukai.
鳥養さん
I'm sorry for wasting my chance.
チャンスを無駄にしてすいませんでした
"What determines whether you can win or not is how aggressive you can be when serving."
サブでどれだけ攻められるかが
勝ち上がていけるかどうかを左右する
Hearing you point that out after the Fukurodani match
and really thinking about it made me understand my role.
梟谷戦での鳥養さんの指摘を聞いて理解して
俺が投入される意味もわかて
そして自分でも勝負できるようになりたいと思て
And then I thought I wanted to be able to play too.
But when push came to shove, I ran away.
それでも土壇場で逃げました
Please.
俺に
もう一回チャンスをください
Give me one more chance!
うせぇなわかてるよ
Stop bugging me.
I already know.
Please put me in there!
俺に行かせてください
京谷もう一本決めろ
Go land another one, Kyoutani!
すまん長い
Sorry!
It went long!
松つん
Mattsun!
Episode Twenty-two:
The Fight of the Previously Spineless
All right!
よしゃあ
くそすまん
Damn it. Sorry!
Aoba Jousai                 Karasuno
まずいのてきてるぞ青城の１６番
This isn't good.
Seijou's number sixteen is finding his groove.
５点差か
They're up by five...
Don't give up!
烏野ファイト
少し下がるべ
Let's move back a bit.
たぶん前に落としてくることはないだろ
I don't think he'll hit one up front.
Yeah.
Right.
ナイサ
Give us a good serve!
Bring it, bring it, bring it!
来い来い来い来い来い
田中
Tanaka!
だしゃぁあ
Yeah!
よしゃあ
Aoba Jousai                 Karasuno
This is just the beginning!
まだまだこからこから
翔陽ナイサ
Give us a good one, Shouyou!
Hey! That guy...
あの子
Pardon me. We're making a substitution.
すいません選手交替します
Hey, it's the scaredy-cat pinch server.
出た「ビビりピンサ」
Oh, it's the guy who played in the Waku South match too.
さきの和久南戦でも出てた奴か
Though I totally understand why he's a scaredy-cat.
まあビビるのはわかるけどね
ピンチのときにサブとか勘弁してほしいもん
I'd hate having to serve when the match is on the line.
That's the guy who was all stiff
from nerves and screwed up, right?
前回ガチガチで失敗しちゃた子だよね
Think he'll be okay?
大丈夫かな
Yeah...
山口１０点獲れ
Yamaguchi, go score ten points!
That'd end the match...
それ試合終わるけど
許す
It's fine.
G-Give it to 'em good, Yamaguchi!
い一発行たれ山口
Y-You gotta keep... keep your cool!
へへいじょ平常心だぞ
ナイサ
Give us a good serve!
Give us a good serve.
ナイサ
思いきり行けよ
Give it your all!
Right!
Three, two, one...
山口一本ナイサブ
Give us a good serve, Yamaguchi!
８秒
Eight seconds.
笛がなてからサブ打つまでに猶予があるのわかてるよな
You know there's that much time after
the whistle blows for you to serve, right?
Yes.
Almost every time, you get surprised by the whistle and immediately toss the ball up to serve.
お前ほぼ毎回笛にびくりしてサブトス上げてたぞ
You don't need to panic.
あんま慌てんなよ
Right.
And, well, you know...
まああとはアレだ
鳥養のとこへ行てきたんだろ
You went to talk to Ukai, right?
Yes.
You chose to do that.
自分の意思で
じゃあお前はもう今までとは決定的に違うプレヤだ
So now you're already a completely different player.
Go out there and do what you want to do.
自分がやりたいと思うことを
やてこいよ
Look at them getting all serious now.
どいつもこいつも雰囲気変えて来やがて
アウト
Let it go!
よしゃぁあああ
All right!
All...
しゃぁああ
...right!
He did it.
忠ィ
Tadashi!
Nice serve!
ナイサ
It stayed in!
入た
私達
We're...
青葉城西の
...supposed to be...
...cheering for Aoba Jousai.
応援でした
Nice serve, Yamaguchi!
Wait, what? Isn't that a bit of an overreaction?
山口ナイス
なに大げさじゃねぇ
たた１点だろ
They only scored one point.
Just like that! Do it again!
いいぞもう一本
Can you believe this guy? A service ace!
ノタチエスだぞおい
一気に追いつくぞ
Catch up in one fell swoop!
すいません
I'm sorry.
It's fine. Don't worry about it.
ドンマイ気にすんな
The ball's pitch changed like crazy.
すげぇ変化したな
俺もアウトだと思たわ
Even I thought it was going out.
これがあるからジャンフロは嫌なんだよ
This is why I hate jump float serves.
すげぇぞ山口
That was awesome, Yamaguchi!
Y-Yeah.
そんなに驚くことじゃないでしょ
It's not that surprising.
There you go agai—
またお前はそうやて
この５ヶ月
In the past five months,
サブだけは誰より練習したんだから
he practiced serving more than anyone else.
このヤロウこのヤロウこのヤロウ
Why, you little...
Do it again, Yamaguchi!
Aoba Jousai                      Karasuno
山口もう一本
思いきり行け
Give it all you've got!
Give it all you've got, Yamaguchi!
思いきり行けよ山口
大丈夫ですよ
He'll be fine.
逃げる方が絶対後からしんどい
You always feel worse after you run away.
て思う方だと思うんで山口も
I'm pretty sure Yamaguchi feels that way too.
A point to change the course of the match...
殻を破る一本ですか
ああそれと
Yeah, and...
反撃の狼煙の一本だ
the start of our counterattack.
切るぞ
Let's stop them here!
Yeah.
仲間に繋ぐことが重要なバレボルの中で
In a sport where passing the ball between players is vital,
serving is the only thing done alone.
サブは唯一孤独なプレですね
Yeah.
You could also say that it's the only way
a player can score a point by themselves.
逆に一人の力で得点できる唯一のプレだとも言える
バレボルが進化していく中で
In the evolution of volleyball, the serve has grown the most in terms of power and importance.
サブは威力も目的も最も進化してきた
そして現代バレボルにおいてサブは
And in modern volleyball,
ブロクという壁に阻まれない究極の攻撃だ
the serve is a powerful attack that
can't be stopped by a wall of blockers.
京谷
Kyoutani!
くそが
Damn it!
さサビスエス２本目
A-Another service ace!
Yes!
よしゃぁああ
All right!
山口ィ
Yamaguchi!
Nice serve.
ナイサ
What the hell?!
なんなのあのサブすげぇ
山口くん
Yamaguchi!
His serve is amazing!
山口ィ
もう一本
Do it again!
Bring it!
さ来い
Got it!
オライ
ジャンフロはオバで捕まえる
You receive jump floats
with overhand digs!
マキナイス
Nice, Makki.
拾われた攻撃が来る
He got it!
They're going to attack now!
命を狙う側から途端に狙われる側に回るような恐怖
There's a certain fear when you change from hunter to hunted.
Iwaizumi!
岩泉
He received it with his body?!
体に当てた
まだまだだ
Not yet... Not yet!
まだサブ権は渡さない
I'm not giving up my turn to serve just yet!
Someone get it!
サンキュ影山
Thanks, Kageyama...
月島ラスト
It's all yours, Tsukishima!
よし/よしゃ
All right!
Tsukki...
A wipe!
ブロクアウト
うまいことブロクにひかけたな
He dealt with the block really well.
月島
Tsukishima!
Aoba Jousai                            Karasuno
これで３連続
That's three points in a row!
もう一本
Do it again.
Yeah!
Hey, Seijou's taking a timeout.
青城タイムアウトか
物理的に流れ切てきたな
They're physically stopping the momentum.
よしゃ
All right!
よしゃあ
青城にタイムアウト取らせるなんてすげぇぞ山口
Making Seijou take a timeout is amazing, Yamaguchi!
Yamaguchi!
山口
Th-Thanks.
ありがとうございます
あの１２番根性入たレシブしやがて
That number twelve sure has some guts with the way he received my spike.
さきのはまぐれだけどね
It was just luck.
すげぇ
Wow.
痛ぇ
It really hurts.
おしゃ勝つぞ
All right! Let's win this!
このまま一気に行け
Keep it up!
俺もあいつらみたいに
I can't do what they do.
自分の体を操りたい
I want full control of my body!
I want to control the ball!
ボルを操りたい
I want to play as equals against good players!
強い奴らと対等に戦いたい
しゃあ
All right!
Yamaguchi!
山口
もう一本
Do it again!
Keep your eye on the ball!
ボルよく見てけよ
Right!
いいか忠
Listen up, Tadashi.
ボルを捕まえる余裕を与えてはいけない
Don't give them the chance to receive the ball.
直線軌道で白帯すれすれを狙て
Aim for right above the white belt of the net...
...and hit!
打つ
持た武器はたた一つ
I only have one weapon I can fight with:
my serve.
与えられるチャンスは僅か一度のサブ権
I got the chance to serve just one time.
その一本にプライドも試合の流れも全て乗せて勝負する
I'm going to fight by putting my pride and
the momentum of the match into that serve.
それが
I am...
ピンチサバ
a pinch server.
It went over!
ネトイン
Is luck on our side now?
運も味方を
No, it's not just that.
いやそれだけじゃねぇよ
これで
Now...
Aoba Jousai                Karasuno
同点
it's tied.
!!
Haikyuu
Second Season
H
a
S
e
i
c
k
y
o
n
u
d
S
e
!
a
s
o
n
Aoba Jousai                Karasuno
Now they're tied!
これで同点
Karasuno caught up!
烏野追いついた
Yamaguchi!
He just barely hit it over the net in the Waku South match too, right?!
山口
あのネトインさきの和久南戦でもあたよね
Tadashi's a lucky boy!
忠ラキボイだな
Yep!
Though it barely went over the net, there's not much similarity between what happened just now and earlier.
同じネトインでも
和久南戦のと今のとでは全然違うよ
山口もう一本
Do it again, Yamaguchi!
During the Waku South match, Tadashi was probably thinking about whether or not the ball would go over.
和久南戦の時忠が考えていたのは恐らくサブが入るか入らないか
Give us a good serve, Yamaguchi!
山口ナイサ
But right now,
今考えているのは
どこに決めるか
he's thinking about where to aim it.
That last serve was the result of going on the offensive.
今のは攻めに行た結果のネトインだ
How awesome, Tadashi!
かこいいじゃん忠
とはいえ本人としては不本意だろうけど
That said, I'm not sure he's entirely aware of it.
Do it again, Yamaguchi!
山口もう一本
For some reason, my serve toss isn't going very high.
どうしてもサブトス低くなちゃうな
Right!
Let's calm down, okay?
落ち着いて
We are calm.
落ち着いてる
Not much we could do about that last one.
まあ今のはしょうがないわな
We'll get the next one.
次次
You guys are so reliable that it makes me a little sad!
さすがお前らしかりしすぎてキャプテン悲しい
It's spinning slightly!
緩い回転がかかてる変化が弱い
The ball's not changing direction!
Got it!
オライ
Nice receive!
ナイスレシブ
I touched it!
ワンタチ
Nice job!
ナイスワンチ
Azumane!
東峰さん
Nice, Kageyama!
ナイス影山
Three blockers!
ブロク３枚
それも高い３枚
And three very tall blockers at that.
In back!
後ろ
アウト
It's going out!
All right!
しゃあ
Nice call, Tanaka!
Whoa, seriously?
田中ナイスジャジ
おいマジかよ
Karasuno...
これて
Aoba Jousai
Karasuno
is at match point!
烏野のマチポイントだぞ
もう一本ナイサ
Give us another good serve!
Yamaguchi...
山口くんは
is the hero of this match.
この試合のヒロですね
Just one more point...
後１点
Just one more point and we win!
後１点で勝てる
決めろ決めてくれ
Land it!
Please, land this serve!
Tadashi!
忠
Yamaguchi! Just one more!
山口もう一本だ
Land this serve!
もう決めちゃえ
いい感じ
That felt good.
俺が取る
I'll get it!
Damn, he's really good.
Nice, Watacchi!
うめぇなクソ
ナイス渡ち
Stop it!
Stop it, please!
止めて/止めろ
All right!
しゃあ
Nice spike!
ナイスキ
We finally ended their streak.
やと切た
How many points did he score, anyway?
一体あいつに何点取られたんだ
That was a marvelous performance!
素晴らしい活躍でしたよ
Good job!
グジョブ
Thank you.
ありがとうございます
You did great, Yamaguchi!
よくやた山口
All right!
Thanks!
That was awesome!
すごいな
すげぇじゃねぇか
Focus on one point at a time!
一本集中
Next time,
次は
I'll score ten points.
１０点取るから
You're on!
負けねぇ
Give us a good serve, Hanamaki!
花巻ナイサ
Yamaguchi gave us this opportunity.
山口が繋いだチャンス
大地さん
Daichi!
We won't let it go to waste!
絶対逃すな
しゃあ
All right!
Nice, Azumane!
ナイスだ東峰
Here they are again!
もう一回来た
Match point!
マチポイント
Go!
行けぇ
All right!
They took a point back so easily.
あさり取り返しますね
They managed to get a fast attack off even while cornered.
この追い詰められた場面で淡々と速攻を
Not to mention, he just hit it straight forward.
しかも真正面突破かよ
If it were me, I'd totally be relying on the ace.
俺だたらエスに頼ちまうところだ
Yeah!
しゃあ
Aoba Jousai                Karasuno
Nice receive!
ナイスレシブ
Watch for the dump!
ツあるぞ
しゃあ
All right!
Nice spike, Tsukishima!
月島ナイスキ
おい動き硬いぞ金田一
Hey, you're stiff, Kindaichi.
Yes! No!
はいいいえ
Which is it?
どちだよ
こちは崖ぷちだ
This is a critical moment for us.
この試合を３年生最後の試合にするわけにはいかない
We can't make this the third-years' last match.
Don't worry about anything else.
余計なことは考えなくていい
どんな時だろうと重要なのは
All you need to focus on is scoring one point at a time.
目の前の一本だけだ
Right!
You can do this, Asahi!
旭決めろ
Give us a good serve!
ナイサ
It went long! Sorry!
長い頼む
しゃあ
All right!
ナイスキ
Nice spike!
あざす
Thanks!
Thanks for saving me!
サンキュ
Seijou sure is good.
さすがだな青城
This next point is huge, but...
次の一本でかいぞ
And
そして
現代バレボルにおいて
in modern volleyball,
サブは
the serve is a powerful attack
ブロクという壁に阻まれない
究極の攻撃となる
that can't be stopped by a wall of blockers.
That was basically a spike.
もはやスパイク
しゃあ
All right!
Rule the Court
Do it again!
Seijou turned it around and is now at set point!
Aoba Jousai                           Karasuno
青城が逆にセトポイント
Will they go on and take this set?
一気に獲ちまうか
Damn it all!
クソが
There's no way just the two of us can handle this.
これは二人では無理だ
Sorry, Asahi, but we need your help.
旭すまん頼む
Sure.
Azumane's going to help receiving the serve too?
東峰くんもサブレシブに
If that's what Sawamura and Nishinoya decided,
then it's probably a good idea.
澤村と西谷の判断ならそのほうがいいだろうな
Oikawa seems to focus more on power than control when he serves.
及川のサブはコントロルより威力重視になているように見える
Rather than him getting a service ace,
ノタチ決められるよりは
どんな形であれ触てあげるほうがずといい
it's better to get the ball up in the air any way they can.
こちだて生川や梟谷のサブを散々受けてきたんだ
They've had plenty of practice with
Ubugawa's and Fukurodani's serves.
It's fine.
大丈夫戦える
They can handle this.
Bring it!
さあ来い
Give us a good one!
ナイサ
Daichi!
大地さん
Yes!
Nice job, Tanaka!
田中ナイス
Kageyama!
影山
Asahi!
旭
旭さん
Nice receive!
ナイスレシブ
All right!
しゃあ
Aoba Jousai                Karasuno
They took back a set!
セト取り返した
I thought Karasuno was gonna take it in straight sets.
烏野ストレトかと思たけどな
Man, we almost had them!
追い詰めたのに
It's fine!
ドンマイ
You're just getting started!
こからこから
Damn!
クソ３セト目しんどいぞ
That third set is gonna be rough!
Let's change gears!
切り替えるぞ
Right!
His serve really is amazing.
やぱすげぇなサブ
You were awesome too, Yamaguchi.
山口のもすごかたぞ
He's much more experienced than I am.
俺とは年季の入り方が違うよ
That might be obvious because he's a third-year, but I think there's more to it than that.
３年生だから当然かもしれないけど
それだけじゃない感じの
More to it?
それだけじゃない
ジャンプサブはだんとつの威力と引きかえに
Jump serves are riskier but provide unparalleled power.
リスクの高いサブだ
He was able to make his serve even more powerful yet not mess it up when they were cornered.
それを威力を上げて
しかも追い詰められた状態で決めるなんて
He's something special.
普通じゃない
Yamaguchi!
山口
Those were nice serves!
ナイスサブだたぞ
Th-Thanks!
あざす
But I've still got a ways to go.
でもまだまだです
Only half of my serves were any good.
半分ぐらいしかいいの打てなかたし
Then be really happy about the half that were good!
じゃよかたほうの半分を盛大に喜べ
Reflection and regret will happen on their own.
反省も後悔も放といとてどうせする
Right now, you need to take a firm grasp on this good feeling to make sure you don't forget it!
今はいいほうの感覚をがちり掴んで忘れねぇようにすんだよ
Really grab it!
ガとな
And then repeat it next time.
そんで次もやてくれ
Right!
結局フルセトか
In the end, we're playing all three sets.
It started with our first practice match.
最初の練習試合
Then the interhigh prelims.
インタハイ予選
And then now.
そんで今
We're having our most intense match yet.
一番濃い試合やてるよな
Difficult opponents...
やりづらい相手
Annoying opponents...
面倒くさい相手
Until last year, we didn't have that much connecting us.
去年まではたいした縁もなかたのに
They were supposed to be beneath us.
格下だたはずなのに
こいつらとはフルでやる宿命
We're destined to play all three sets against these guys.
Aoba Jousai                     Karasuno
The third set...
ファイナルセト
This is our final battle!
最後の勝負だ
That was amazing, Yamaguchi!
すごかたよ山口くん
Th-Thanks, Yachi.
あありがとう谷地さん
Just in case, I had an AED, stretcher, and coffin prepared,
but they weren't necessary at all!
私もしもの時のために
AEDとか担架とか棺桶とか用意してたんだけど
全然必要なかたね
Huh?! Wasn't there something strange at the end of that list?!
最後なんか変なの混じてなかた
Episode Twenty-three:
"Team"
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
次回ハイキュチム
"'Team.'"